<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Kedianan Radik</title><link>https://kediananradik.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Kedianan Radik</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 09:31:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kediananradik.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>4 Keys to Building Confidence in God When Life Falls Apart</title><link>https://kediananradik.github.io/posts/47902558-4-keys-to-building-confidence-in-god-when-life-falls-apart/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 09:31:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kediananradik.github.io/posts/47902558-4-keys-to-building-confidence-in-god-when-life-falls-apart/</guid><description>We all encounter difficult times in our lives, times when we may feel like life is falling apart. But even in these dark and uncertain moments, God offers a way out of despair and fear through a growing trust in him. As you engage these four principles, may you find fresh assurance in God's constant love, care, and power to transform your circumstances, as you become more confident in him.</description></item><item><title>How Should Christians Approach Progress in Technology?</title><link>https://kediananradik.github.io/posts/86742834-how-should-christians-approach-progress-in-technology/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 11:19:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kediananradik.github.io/posts/86742834-how-should-christians-approach-progress-in-technology/</guid><description>With each new technological advancement, our lives become more and more intertwined with the innovative products created as a result. Few areas of life are left untouched by the power of technology. While the tech industry expands at a remarkable pace, it can be hard to sift through the ethical implications of all these changes. As Christians, we must ask, “How should we approach the progression of technology?”
As followers of Jesus Christ, we possess a unique responsibility to wisely consider the impact of any given subject, and this is no different with technology.</description></item><item><title>The Good and the Bad of Christian Fundamentalism</title><link>https://kediananradik.github.io/posts/90962038-the-good-and-the-bad-of-christian-fundamentalism/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 13:29:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kediananradik.github.io/posts/90962038-the-good-and-the-bad-of-christian-fundamentalism/</guid><description>Christian fundamentalism is an aspect of evangelical Protestantism that emphasizes strict adherence to biblical inerrancy, as well as other traditional doctrines. To many, the term "fundamentalism" conjures images of rigid and dogmatic people who focus on legalistic rules and a rejection of all non-Christian religions. This perception often leads to negative portrayals of such believers and their way of life. Although parts of this portrayal may be true, the good that Christian fundamentalism provides should not be overlooked.</description></item><item><title>One Key Reason Why Church Consultations Fail</title><link>https://kediananradik.github.io/posts/67874169-one-key-reason-why-church-consultations-fail/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 08:36:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kediananradik.github.io/posts/67874169-one-key-reason-why-church-consultations-fail/</guid><description>Increasingly, a new form of aid to churches in trouble has appeared—professional church consultations. These are often considered, even by other respected church leaders, as a last resort—sometimes the last ditch effort to turn a church back around, before it’s too late. The primary reason these consultations have come into being is that many congregations get mired in a rut, leading to the inability of current leadership to move the church forward in a positive way.</description></item><item><title>What Does Jesus Teach Us about God's End-Times Plan?</title><link>https://kediananradik.github.io/posts/25106337-what-does-jesus-teach-us-about-god-s-end-times-plan/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 13:14:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kediananradik.github.io/posts/25106337-what-does-jesus-teach-us-about-god-s-end-times-plan/</guid><description>The concept of the end-times, or the "last days," is found in almost every Christian Bible. It refers to the time in the future when the sovereign Lord, Jesus Christ, will return to reign over planet Earth. How the end-times will unfold is a question that has generated much debate, but from the Scriptures, we can gather some basic truths.
To correctly understand what the Bible teaches about God's end-times plan, we must first recognize the primary and foundational message that Jesus portrays in the four Gospels.</description></item><item><title>Self-Care: Selfish Habit or Holy Endeavor?</title><link>https://kediananradik.github.io/posts/89242650-self-care-selfish-habit-or-holy-endeavor/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 12:51:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kediananradik.github.io/posts/89242650-self-care-selfish-habit-or-holy-endeavor/</guid><description>Many in our culture regard self-care as a selfish habit. One can sense the disapproval behind comments such as, “She’s so self-absorbed; she spends all her time at the gym.” We sometimes even hear such admonitions within church circles, as if the call to deny ourself (Luke 9:23) means total self-abnegation. Let’s explore the idea of self-care within biblical and psychological frameworks.
The Danger of Extreme Neglect Excessive selflessness — particularly when it ignores one’s physical, emotional, or spiritual well-being — can be damaging.</description></item><item><title>Why Should Christians Evaluate What Their Lives Are Built On?</title><link>https://kediananradik.github.io/posts/84705405-why-should-christians-evaluate-what-their-lives-are-built-on/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 13:45:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kediananradik.github.io/posts/84705405-why-should-christians-evaluate-what-their-lives-are-built-on/</guid><description>"Therefore everyone who hears these words of Mine, and acts according to them, may be compared to a wise man who built his house upon the rock. And the rain fell, and the floods came, and the winds blew and slammed against that house; and yet it did not fall, because it had been founded on the rock" (Matt 7:24-25).
Jesus used the illustration of a house on a firm foundation to emphasize the importance of building our lives on His words.</description></item><item><title>Is it My Responsibility to Help the Widows and Orphans?</title><link>https://kediananradik.github.io/posts/34022375-is-it-my-responsibility-to-help-the-widows-and-orphans/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 15:45:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kediananradik.github.io/posts/34022375-is-it-my-responsibility-to-help-the-widows-and-orphans/</guid><description>The concept of caring for widows and orphans is deeply rooted in Scripture and demonstrates God’s heart. In biblical times, these particular groups were at considerable risk due to a lack of social security, inheritance, and family to support them. Thus, the concept of caring for widows and orphans was a prominent theme in God’s commandments.
In today’s world, social institutions have evolved tremendously. However, the underlying values of love, care, and compassion continue to be crucial.</description></item><item><title>Why the Church Should Take Responsibility for Its Liberties and Freedoms</title><link>https://kediananradik.github.io/posts/91000480-why-the-church-should-take-responsibility-for-its-liberties-and-freedoms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 05:30:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kediananradik.github.io/posts/91000480-why-the-church-should-take-responsibility-for-its-liberties-and-freedoms/</guid><description>The following paper, which was prepared for a conference on the relationship between church and state in the early modern period held at the University of Cambridge in 2009, takes a long view of this topic to explain why it is so important for the Church to take responsibility for its rights and liberties. The argument rests on the premise that the history of religious liberty and the liberties of the Church are deeply intertwined.</description></item><item><title>9 Lessons for New Christians ... And Old Ones</title><link>https://kediananradik.github.io/posts/16085264-9-lessons-for-new-christians-and-old-ones/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 10:31:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kediananradik.github.io/posts/16085264-9-lessons-for-new-christians-and-old-ones/</guid><description>At the start of every new year, a lot of people start making new resolutions on the hopes of changing and improving their lives. Many of these goals are often specific to health, money, relationships, or career. While being new Christians, we may want to use the freshness and enthusiasm of a new year to resolve to focus on our faith journey and the development of certain spiritual habits.
Here are nine lessons that can serve as a sort of spiritual resolution, whether we're new to the faith or we've been walking in it for a while.</description></item><item><title>How to Actually Treat Other Believers Like Family</title><link>https://kediananradik.github.io/posts/23978457-how-to-actually-treat-other-believers-like-family/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 20:38:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kediananradik.github.io/posts/23978457-how-to-actually-treat-other-believers-like-family/</guid><description>“Treating fellow believers like family” is often mentioned in Christian communities, but figuring out how to do that can feel rather hazy. It's easy to say that we should care for each other, “bear one another's burdens," and "be hospitable” (Galatians 6:2; Romans 12:13). But without clear guidance, our attempts to embody these exhortations can fall flat, leading to awkward situations or unmet expectations.
The Apostle Paul, a believer who intimately knew God's family and had no shortage of experience within the early Christian communities, provides helpful guidance for embodying this ideal.</description></item><item><title>Why Are There So Many Ideas about Heaven That Are Not Biblical?</title><link>https://kediananradik.github.io/posts/81517178-why-are-there-so-many-ideas-about-heaven-that-are-not-biblical/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kediananradik.github.io/posts/81517178-why-are-there-so-many-ideas-about-heaven-that-are-not-biblical/</guid><description>A widespread misconception about heaven has been fueled not only by common people but even by well-meaning ministers and theologians. The incorrect image of heaven, some would say, is almost an unavoidable cultural inheritance from Plato, from the Greeks and Romans; but this is a misconstrued perception. The principal reason, which will be explained below, for so many ideas about heaven that are not biblical can be traced to a failure to pay heed to the Bible itself.</description></item><item><title>Why People Are Losing Their Religion (and How the Church Can Respond)</title><link>https://kediananradik.github.io/posts/69129408-why-people-are-losing-their-religion-and-how-the-church-can-respond/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 18:44:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kediananradik.github.io/posts/69129408-why-people-are-losing-their-religion-and-how-the-church-can-respond/</guid><description>According to a 2012 Pew Research Center report, one-fifth of all religiously affiliated people have either left their religion or dropped out of organized religion altogether in what’s known as the “nones.” The rise of the nones is a trend in many Western countries, including the U.S., Canada, Germany, Ireland, Australia and the United Kingdom. In the U.S, for example, only 77 percent of millennials identify as religious compared to 90 percent of baby boomers.</description></item><item><title>Why Christians Can Be Bad at Being Kind</title><link>https://kediananradik.github.io/posts/35500511-why-christians-can-be-bad-at-being-kind/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 22:09:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kediananradik.github.io/posts/35500511-why-christians-can-be-bad-at-being-kind/</guid><description>The topic of kindness is not one that usually elicits intense theological debates amongst Christians, and it should not, for being kind is generally seen as a good thing. However, just because a concept is seemingly straightforward and easy to adopt, doesn't necessarily mean that its reality in the lives of genuine believers is trouble-free. The contention of this article is that the inconsistencies we sometimes witness between proclaimed Christian belief and demonstrated human behavior can in part be explained by an often-overlooked paradox, which is the fact that Christians can at times be bad at being kind.</description></item><item><title>Guilt and the Great Deception in the Christian Life</title><link>https://kediananradik.github.io/posts/25835934-guilt-and-the-great-deception-in-the-christian-life/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 11:36:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kediananradik.github.io/posts/25835934-guilt-and-the-great-deception-in-the-christian-life/</guid><description>This article is about the potent subject of guilt. Although guilt is usually perceived to have only a negative impact on a person’s life, in this article we will look at the way guilt can become a dangerous deception in the Christian life, particularly if misunderstood and misapplied. Jesus, in His ministry of reconciliation, came to free us from the burden of guilt, and we will see how the guilty conscience can be manipulated and exploited to keep us from the fullness of that freedom.</description></item><item><title>Why Pastors Struggle to Ask for Help (And How to Get Past It)</title><link>https://kediananradik.github.io/posts/49317154-why-pastors-struggle-to-ask-for-help-and-how-to-get-past-it/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 03:10:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kediananradik.github.io/posts/49317154-why-pastors-struggle-to-ask-for-help-and-how-to-get-past-it/</guid><description>Pastoral ministry can be a very isolating calling. Many pastors have a misguided sense that the chief requirement for the work they do is to be superhuman or self-sufficient—to never admit to weakness or vulnerability. It's a common stereotype, but unfortunately, far too many pastors do indeed hold to this erroneous standard.
As an inner voice tells these individuals that they must always be strong, never showing their weakness to others, the ability to ask for help slowly fades away.</description></item><item><title>Why Do Christians Emphasize Hell Instead of Not Being with God in Heaven?</title><link>https://kediananradik.github.io/posts/46008360-why-do-christians-emphasize-hell-instead-of-not-being-with-god-in-heaven/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 18:10:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kediananradik.github.io/posts/46008360-why-do-christians-emphasize-hell-instead-of-not-being-with-god-in-heaven/</guid><description>Christians, and perhaps more specifically Evangelicals, often emphasize the reality of eternal punishment, or Hell, when sharing the gospel. This reality may seem to overshadow or focus more energy on the potential negatives of spiritual life, rather than highlighting the joy, hope, and fulfillment a relationship with Christ provides. From a theological perspective, this may cause some to question the effectiveness of this approach: Why do Christians, including myself, place so much emphasis on Hell?</description></item></channel></rss>